Aida Blinstrubyte

Phone: (630) 854-3112 | Email: a.blinstrubyte@outlook.com| Chicago, IL

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aidablinstrubyte/ | Portfolio: https://gentle-atoll-25305.herokuapp.com |

GitHub: https://github.com/aidabyte

Full Stack web developer with a background in Cosmetology. Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from Northwestern University in Chicago. Newly developed skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, APIs, MySQL, Node.js, React, and responsive web design. Strengths in teamwork, communication, and collaboration. Known for having a great eye in design and enthusiasm for developing apps that are mobile friendly. With every project my goal is to have the user have the best experience possible and everything to be properly functioning. I'm excited to utilize my experience from my cosmetology background such as critical thinking and evaluating results to choose the best solution and solve problems that occur, along with my technical skills, and a meticulous eye for detail making me an asset to any driven team.

Technical Skills

- Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL
- Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Passport.

Projects

Bobbies Hobbies | GitHub: https://github.com/eptomlinson/BobbysHobbys

Deployed:https://boiling-scrubland-76321.herokuapp.com

- **Summary**: A user can post their own hobby that they are interested in by providing an image, description, and cost. They are able to view and like the hobbies that other users have uploaded.
- Role: Front End Web Design and log in feature
- Tools: React, JavaScript, Passport, Bootstrap

Employee Directory| GitHub: https://github.com/aidabyte/employee-directory

Deployed: https://obscure-reef-68172.herokuapp.com

- **Summary**: A directory of employees that consist of the employees name, age, picture, and country. An employer can access a specific employee by typing in their name or the first letters of their name. Also, can search in alphabetical order.
- Role: Author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Axios, Bootstrap, Node.js, React

Note Taker| GitHub: https://github.com/aidabyte/Note-Taker-Hw

Deployed: https://serene-anchorage-84914.herokuapp.com/notes

- **Summary**: A digital notepad created to save, delete, or add notes so the user can remember what they wrote down when it was important. If you refresh the page the notes will still be there.
- Role: Author
- **Tools:** Node.js, Express, Postman

Experience

Smith & Davis Salon / Hair Colorist

MAY 2018 - OCTOBER 2020 CHICAGO IL

- Accomplished building a portfolio with professional photoshoots and clientele
- Created and presented portfolios to document various hairstyles and concepts
- Collaborated with other hair cutters to determine the client's overall hair appearance

Siren Salon / Assistant/Front Desk

JUNE 2016 - MARCH 2018, CHICAGO IL

- Gained more knowledge in the industry by attending monthly hands-on education classes
- Communicated with stylist's clients effectively pertaining to their needs
- Greeted clients, answered phone calls, and booked appointments

Education

Northwestern University/ Coding Bootcamp/Full Stack Flex Certificate SEPTEMBER 2020 - DECEMBER 2020, CHICAGO IL

Pivot Point International Academy/Cosmetology OCTOBER 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2015, BLOOMINGDALE IL